List<Map<String, dynamic>> partTwoQuestions = [
  {
    'question':
    'A patient with congestive heart failure presents with acute shortness of breath. Which intervention should the nurse prioritize?',
    'answers': [
      'Administer a diuretic.',
      'Provide supplemental oxygen.',
      'Administer a beta-blocker.',
      'Perform chest compressions.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'A patient with type 1 diabetes mellitus is experiencing symptoms of hypoglycemia. Which intervention should the nurse perform first?',
    'answers': [
      'Administer insulin.',
      'Provide a carbohydrate-rich snack.',
      'Check blood glucose level.',
      'Assess for diabetic ketoacidosis.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'During a neurological assessment, a patient exhibits decerebrate posturing. What area of the brain is likely affected?',
    'answers': [
      'Cerebral cortex.',
      'Brainstem.',
      'Cerebellum.',
      'Limbic system.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'When assessing a newborn for developmental dysplasia of the hip (DDH), which physical finding is indicative of this condition?',
    'answers': [
      'Limited range of motion.',
      'Symmetric thigh creases.',
      'Positive Ortolani maneuver.',
      'Normal femoral pulses.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'Which medication should the nurse be cautious when administering to a patient with a history of peptic ulcer disease?',
    'answers': [
      'Acetaminophen (Tylenol).',
      'Ibuprofen (Advil).',
      'Aspirin (ASA).',
      'Omeprazole (Prilosec).',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'A patient with a suspected head injury has a Glasgow Coma Scale (GCS) score of 8. What does this score indicate?',
    'answers': [
      'Mild brain injury.',
      'Severe brain injury.',
      'Moderate brain injury.',
      'Normal neurological function.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'Which of the following medications is a bronchodilator commonly used in the management of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)?',
    'answers': [
      'Furosemide (Lasix).',
      'Lisinopril (Prinivil).',
      'Albuterol (Proventil).',
      'Warfarin (Coumadin).',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'A patient is receiving heparin therapy for deep vein thrombosis (DVT). Which laboratory test is used to monitor the effectiveness of heparin?',
    'answers': [
      'Prothrombin time (PT).',
      'International normalized ratio (INR).',
      'Activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT).',
      'Platelet count.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'When caring for a patient with multiple sclerosis (MS), the nurse should prioritize interventions to address which symptom?',
    'answers': [
      'Hypertension.',
      'Hyperglycemia.',
      'Fatigue.',
      'Constipation.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'What is the primary purpose of mechanical ventilation in critically ill patients?',
    'answers': [
      'Providing oxygenation.',
      'Reducing respiratory rate.',
      'Preventing aspiration.',
      'Improving cardiac output.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },


  {
    'question':
    'Which mode of mechanical ventilation provides the greatest patient control over their breathing?',
    'answers': [
      'Assist-control ventilation.',
      'Pressure support ventilation.',
      'Synchronized intermittent mandatory ventilation (SIMV).',
      'Volume control ventilation.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'In pressure-controlled ventilation, which parameter is set and maintained by the ventilator?',
    'answers': [
      'Tidal volume.',
      'Inspiratory pressure.',
      'Respiratory rate.',
      'Expiratory time.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'What is the primary disadvantage of using high positive end-expiratory pressure (PEEP) in mechanical ventilation?',
    'answers': [
      'Risk of barotrauma.',
      'Increased oxygenation.',
      'Reduced work of breathing.',
      'Improved lung compliance.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'Which ventilator parameter should be adjusted to increase the mean airway pressure?',
    'answers': [
      'FiO2 (Fraction of Inspired Oxygen).',
      'Tidal volume.',
      'Inspiratory time.',
      'Respiratory rate.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'What condition is characterized by decreased lung compliance, increased airway resistance, and decreased oxygenation despite mechanical ventilation?',
    'answers': [
      'Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome (ARDS).',
      'Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD).',
      'Pneumonia.',
      'Pulmonary embolism.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'When adjusting the FiO2 on a ventilator, what is the goal in maintaining adequate oxygenation while minimizing the risk of oxygen toxicity?',
    'answers': [
      'Increase FiO2 to 100%.',
      'Keep FiO2 as low as possible.',
      'Adjust FiO2 based on the patient\'s age.',
      'Maintain FiO2 between 30% and 60%.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'What is the primary purpose of positive-pressure ventilation during cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR)?',
    'answers': [
      'Maintain oxygenation and ventilation.',
      'Prevent aspiration.',
      'Stabilize blood pressure.',
      'Induce hyperventilation.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'Which ventilator mode is commonly used for patients with neuromuscular diseases, such as ALS?',
    'answers': [
      'Assist-control ventilation.',
      'Pressure support ventilation.',
      'Bi-level positive airway pressure (BiPAP).',
      'SIMV ventilation.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'What is the significance of the "I:E ratio" in mechanical ventilation?',
    'answers': [
      'It determines the inspiratory flow rate.',
      'It indicates the patient\'s level of comfort.',
      'It represents the ratio of inspiratory to expiratory time.',
      'It controls the ventilator\'s alarms.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
    'Which parameter is monitored to assess the effectiveness of mechanical ventilation in terms of reducing the work of breathing?',
    'answers': [
      'Peak inspiratory pressure (PIP).',
      'Plateau pressure.',
      'Minute ventilation.',
      'Respiratory rate.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },

  {
    'question':
    'Which class of antibiotics is known for its potential to cause tendonitis and tendon rupture?',
    'answers': [
      'Penicillins',
      'Aminoglycosides',
      'Quinolones',
      'Cephalosporins',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'question':
    'Which type of hepatitis is primarily transmitted through the fecal-oral route and is associated with contaminated food and water?',
    'answers': ['Hepatitis A', 'Hepatitis B', 'Hepatitis C', 'Hepatitis D',],
    'correctIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'question':
    'What is the primary site for gas exchange in the respiratory system?',
    'answers': ['Pharynx', 'Bronchi', 'Alveoli', 'Trachea',],
    'correctIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'question':
    'Which electrolyte imbalance is characterized by muscle weakness, constipation, and ECG changes such as prolonged QT intervals?',
    'answers': ['Hypernatremia', 'Hyperkalemia', 'Hypocalcemia', 'Hypokalemia',],
    'correctIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'question':
    'In which stage of labor does the cervix dilate from 10 centimeters to birth of the baby?',
    'answers': ['First stage', 'Second stage', 'Third stage', 'Fourth stage',],
    'correctIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'question':
    'Which of the following medications is an anticoagulant that works by inhibiting vitamin K-dependent clotting factors?',
    'answers': [
      'Warfarin (Coumadin)',
      'Heparin',
      'Aspirin',
      'Clopidogrel (Plavix)',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'question':
    'Which layer of the skin contains blood vessels, nerves, and hair follicles?',
    'answers': ['Epidermis', 'Dermis', 'Subcutaneous tissue', 'Hypodermis',],
    'correctIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the primary function of the adrenal medulla?',
    'answers': [
      'Regulation of blood pressure',
      'Regulation of blood sugar',
      'Secretion of stress hormones such as adrenaline',
      'Filtration of blood',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'question':
    'Which of the following is a key symptom of Guillain-Barr√© syndrome?',
    'answers': [
      'Muscle rigidity',
      'Muscle atrophy',
      'Muscle spasticity',
      'Ascending muscle weakness',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'question':
    'What is the purpose of the Glasgow Coma Scale (GCS) in assessing a patient\'s neurological status?',
    'answers': [
      'To measure blood glucose levels',
      'To evaluate pain tolerance',
      'To assess the level of consciousness',
      'To determine blood pressure',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2
  }
];